Guide to the Collection of Library Bookplates
Yale University Arts Library
Collection of Library Bookplates
1735-1969
1875-1925
BKP 80
Yale University Arts Library
1.25
(3 boxes)
This collection contains institutional bookplates for a variety of libraries.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Yale Bookplate Collection was formerly housed in Sterling Memorial Library. The collection was incorporated into the Arts of the Book Collection in 1984 and then moved to the Seeley G. Mudd Library in 1990. In 2011, it was transferred to the Robert B. Haas Family Arts Library.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains institutional bookplates for a variety of libraries. A few bookplates for private patrons are also interspersed.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Bookplates – Mounted. II. Bookplates – Unmounted. III. Bookplates – Donors.
Library bookplates; Bookplates
- Bookplates – Mounted, Series I
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by the name of the library or institution.
  - Gray Mounts
    - Adams – American, 1922-1944 undated; 20 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Appalachian – Biblioteca Municipal, Rio de Janeiro, 1877-1952 undated; 16 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Boston – Boyd, 1917 undated; 24 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bridge Memorial Library – Cambridge School for Girls, 1894-1934 undated; 19 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Cambridge Public Library – Cincinnati, undated; 22 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Citadel – Copley Greene Library, undated; 20 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Corporation of Walsall – Duluth, 1899 1933 undated; 20 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Duxbury – G. Frampton's Library, 1912-1946 undated; 20 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Franklin Institute Library – Glasgow, 1912-1917 undated; 20 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Scope and Contents
      This folder includes a typescript letter dated January 14, 1952, from Hamilton Vaughan Bail to Donald G. Wing.
    - Goucher – Hartwell, 1877-1910 undated; 19 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Harvard, 1892-1921 undated; 21 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Harvard, 1893 undated; 18 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Hathaway House – Inner Temple, undated; 17 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Jablin – Leithieullier, 1895-1931 undated; 20 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - W. S. Lewis – Lynn, 1942 undated; 20 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Maine – Massachusetts, Library of the General Court, 1919-1924 undated; 21 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - McCracken – Myers, 1838-1902 undated; 19 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Nahant – New York Yacht Club Library, 1900 1904 undated; 20 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Newark – Northwestern, 1904-1947 undated; 18 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Oliver – Lord Pentland, 1894 undated; 20 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Perceval – Prudential, undated; 18 items (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Radcliffe – Saint Mary's High School, 1859-1923 undated; 21 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Salem – Syracuse, 1883-1914 undated; 19 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Taylor Institution – University Club of Los Angeles, 1917-1942 undated; 20 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - University College Library, Nottingham – University of Maryland, undated; 20 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - University of Michigan – Wolcott and Litchfield Circulating Library, 1899 undated; 21 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Women's City Club of Boston – Yale Club of New York City, 1830-1905 undated; 7 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Yale – Zion Research Library, 1875-1956 undated; 37 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Unidentified, 1952 undated; 16 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous Mounts
    - American Library Association – Yale, 1891-1969 undated; 14 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Authors Club Library – University Club, 1803-1909 undated; 19 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Bradford – Studio Club, undated; 7 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - American Institute of Electrical Engineers – Wellsboro, 1888-1922 undated; 22 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Amherst – Young Men's Christian Association, 1803-1909 undated; 23 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Miscellaneous, 1830 undated; 21 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Bookplates – Unmounted, Series II
  Loose bookplates arranged alphabetically by the name of the library or institution.
  - American Antiquarian Society – Bowdoin, 1875-1925 undated; 24 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Brooklyn – Columbia, 1904 undated; 29 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Connecticut College for Women – Dublin, Greene's Library, 1901-1912 undated; 10 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Easthampton – Glasgow, 1819-1926 undated; 31 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    This folder includes two premium or prize bookplates.
  - Goodspeed's – Hill School, 1894-1914 undated; 11 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Historical Society of Pennsylvania – Musicians of Los Angeles, undated; 18 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Nahant – Rowfant, 1900-1911 undated; 22 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Royal Dublin Society – Thoroton Society, 1901-1917 undated; 16 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Trinity College – University of Aberdeen, 1735-1920 undated; 20 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    This folder includes several examples of premium or prize bookplates.
  - University of California – University of Rochester, 1927-1938; 21 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - United States Military Academy – Williams College, undated; 22 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Wilson's Grammar School – Young Men's Christian Association, 1874-1914 undated; 14 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Bookplates – Donors, Series III
  Arranged alphabetically by the name of the donor, either institution or individual.
  - Berea College Library, undated; 1 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - City College of New York, undated; 9 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Columbia, 1895-1947 undated; 120 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Corey, George Henry, 1906 undated; 17 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    This folder also includes an example of the personal ex-libris of George Henry Corey, designed and signed by Rockwell Kent.
  - Muirhead, Arnold, 1947 undated; 2 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Phillips Exeter Academy, 1955 undated; 50 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Yale University Press, 1949 undated; 4 (Box 3, Folder 54)